We'll rank all the students on a scale of A to F
（谷尋）全生徒を　ゲノムレゾナンス指数で
ＡからＦにランク分けし→
based on their genomic resonance values,
and you, Shu, will reign over them.
その頂点に
集　お前が君臨する。→
いわば　ヴォイドランク制だな。
You could call it the Void ranking system.
I'll make the boo-boo... all better!
（祭）痛いの痛いの　飛んでけー！
（一同）おー！
あの子のヴォイドは
ホント　すごいよな！
That girl's Void is really something, huh!
I want her to heal me, too.
俺も癒やしてほしい。
（生徒）この前のケガも
すごく奇麗に治してくれたし→
You healed up that injury really well before.
Thanks so much!
ホント　ありがとね。
（祭）ううん。
No problem.
それに比べて
私のヴォイドなんて…。
Compared to you, my Void is just...
（集）大事なのは
ヴォイドの強弱じゃなくて→
The important thing isn't
how strong your Void is;
みんなのために働くことなんで。
it's how you work for other people, so...
Um, keep up the good work.
（集）あの…　頑張ってください。
♪♪～
A symphony of disintegration resounds
The falling rain has the exact timbre of tears
Realize
Those eyes are for recognizing each other with
Those voices are for
conveying our feelings with
Those hands are for joining
hands with our loved ones
All you living beings who can hear this song
The truth lies within your heart
And even when you're traveling a stormy sea
It will give you a strength
That will never flinch
《ひととおり　ヴォイドの
調査こそ行ったが→
We did perform a general Void exam,
Confession
谷尋の
ヴォイドランクの提案を→
but I couldn't accept
Yahiro's Void ranking plan.
僕は受け入れられなかった》
"Always Consult with the Person in Charge"
《みんなを　嫌な気分にしながら
やる管理なんて→
I just don't think supervising everyone
in a way that makes them feel bad
can possibly go well.
うまくいくと思えない》
《といっても　今の校内に
まったく問題がないかって→
Still...
I can't honestly say there are no
problems in our school right now.
そんなことは
とても言えないんだけど…》
（数藤）鶫姉さん。
俺ら　警備班はハードな訓練で→
'Scuse me, Tsugumi! Our training
for the security team is so hardcore,
I'm feeling super-starving...
超腹ぺこなんすけど。
（鶫）だから何！？
So what?!
N-Nothing! Nothing at all!
（数藤）い…　いえ。
何でもないっす！
（シャッター音）
We've got all kinds of problems.
《色々と問題は多い》
《レッドラインも
日々　刻々と前進してきている》
And the red line is getting
closer and closer all the time.
《僕らが　しっかりしないと》
If we don't keep it together...
駄目だ。
We're in trouble.
ワクチンや　武器　弾薬の確保も
バリケードの設営も→
We haven't even finished
half the work on our plans
to secure vaccine and ammo
supplies or set up a barricade.
予定の半分も進んでない。
（谷尋）だから　ランク制を敷けと
言ってるんだ。
This is why I keep telling you
to implement the ranking system.
上下関係を徹底すれば
人は　倍　働く。
People work twice as hard
when there's a clear hierarchy.
そんなの
受け入れられるわけないよ。
I just can't accept that!
ヴォイドで差別するなんて。
（谷尋）差別じゃない。　区別だ。
Discriminating against
people because of their Voids...
It's not discrimination. It's distinction.
That's just semantics, you know?
そんなの詭弁だよね。
If they feel like it's discrimination,
it's the same thing, isn't it!
された　みんなが差別って感じたら同じじゃん。
（綾瀬）あんたの気持ちは
分からないでもないけど→
It's not that I don't understand how you feel,
レッドラインは止まらないのよ。
大丈夫なわけ？
but the red line isn't going to stop.
Do you think that's okay?
それは　そうだけど…。
Well, you've got a point, but...
（鶫）「同情は　毒にしかならない」
Sympathy only gets people hurt.
That's what Gai said!
…って　涯が言ってた。
I bet you just don't want people to hate you.
君。　人に嫌われたくない
だけじゃないの？
違うよ！
That's not it!
（いのり）集は　どうしたいの？
えっ？
What do you want to do, Shu?
みんながじゃなくて→
Not the others... What do you want to do?
集は　どうしたいの？
あっ。
（颯太）うん？
Thanks.
ありがとう。
（祭・綾瀬・鶫）ハァ～。
（祭）あの…　綾瀬さん。→
Um, Ayase... what's going
on between Yuzuriha and Shu?
楪さんと集って
どうなってるんでしょう？
（綾瀬）えっ。　何で　私に聞くの？
Huh? Why are you asking me?
Oh, I want to know that too!
Come on, spill it, Aya!
あっ！　それは　私も知りたーい。
ねえねえ　どうなの？　綾姉。
Like I said, why ask me?
だから　何で　私に聞くの！？
さっき　ドキッとしたんです。
I was startled back there.
集は　ランク制
反対だと思ってたのに…。
I thought Shu was against the ranking system...
いのりは　集に
迷いがあることを見抜いてたよね。
Inori could tell that Shu was uncertain.
You know, I was happy that Shu became president.
（祭）私　集が会長になって
うれしかったんです。→
I thought he could be a kind king...
集なら　優しい王様になれるって。
（鶫）王様？
"King"?
アハハ！　そうだね。
確かに　ここは　集の王国ね。
Yeah, this pretty much
is Shu's kingdom, isn't it?
If you're going to tease me,
forget I said anything!
からかうなら　もう　いいです！
（鶫）ふぅ～。
ユー　とっとと　告っちゃいなよ。
Hurry up and confess to him, you!
えっ…！
（綾瀬）鶫！　あんた　いきなり何！？
Tsugumi! Where did that come from?
だって　こんなご時世だもん
言ったもん勝ちだと違う？
Just look at the times we're living in!
Nothing ventured, nothing gained, am I right?
（颯太）何だよ　それ！
何が区別だよ。→
What the hell?!
"Distinction," my butt!
It's plain old discrimination!
ただの差別じゃねえか！
そ…　そうだよね。
I-I think so, too.
（颯太）見損なったぜ　集！
I can't believe you'd use
a cruel system like that!
そんな　ひでえシステムを
採用するなんて！
I'm disappointed in you, Shu!
No, I'm not going to! You know I wouldn't!
いや　しないよ。
するわけ　ないじゃない！
そうか。
そうだよな。
Oh.
Yeah...
ごめん　集！
見損なったとか言っちまって。
I'm sorry I said I was disappointed, Shu!
Should I bow?
土下座でいいか？
許してくれ！
Forgive me!
Hey, you don't have to go that far...
いいよ　そこまでしなくても。
（颯太）じゃあ　握手。
Shake hands, then.
This means we're friends again, right?
これで仲直りな。
Yeah...
うん。
（颯太）じゃあ
いっちょ　吠えてみるか。
Okay then, let's give a howl.
吠える？
Howl?
Times like these, a good shout
together deepens the friendship.
こういうときは　一緒に
大声を出すと　友情が深まるんだ。
いろんな映画で見たろ？
You've seen it in tons of movies, right?
（颯太）人間に
ランクなんか　つけるな！！
Never assign people ranks!
ほら。　友達を差別するな！！
するな。
Don't discriminate against your friends!
Don't do it...
（颯太）いのりちゃん好きだー！
えっ　それ関係ないでしょ！
I love Inori!
What's that got to do with it?
いいんだよ　青春なんだから。
ほら。　集も　何か言えよ。
We're young. We're supposed to do this stuff.
Go on, you say something, Shu.
Er...
えっと…。
僕は　生徒会長になんて
向いてないんだー！
I'm not cut out to be student council president!
アハハハ！
そうだよな。
Yeah, so true.
人に嫌われたくなくて
何が　いけないんだー！
What's wrong with not
wanting people to hate me?!
What's wrong with wanting the girls to like me?!
女の子にモテたくて
何が　いけないんだー！！
Down with the Void ranking system!
（颯太・集）
ヴォイドランク制　反対！！
Hey, guys! I...
みんな　僕は…。
（亞里沙）駄目ね。→
It's no good. No matter how
you calculate it, this isn't enough.
どう計算しても足りないわ。
（花音）投薬量を減らしたら？
What if we injected smaller amounts?
駄目だ。
一定量を投与しなければ。
We can't. It has to be the fixed dosage.
あっ。　大変だ　集。
ワクチンが足りない。
We've got a problem, Shu.
We don't have enough vaccine.
えっ！
（亞里沙）取りあえず→
Well, let's at least prioritize
securing Ouma's dosage.
桜満君の分だけは
優先的に確保しましょう。
そんな…。
僕だけ特別扱いなんて。
Wait, I shouldn't get special treatment...
お前が発症したら
誰が　この学校を守るんだ？
If you get sick, who's
going to protect this school?
あ…。
お前だけじゃない。→
It's not just you. The most useful
Voids should be given priority, too.
この状況で　役に立つヴォイドは
優先されるべきだ。→
ヴォイドの
ランク順になっている。→
"Rank F"
Here's everyone in order of rank.
こいつに従って
不平等に　ワクチンを配るんだ。
We'll distribute the vaccine
unequally based on this.
《颯太！　最低のＦランクに！？》
Souta's in the lowest rank?
（谷尋）生き残るためには
それしかない。
We have no choice if we want to survive.
Decide, President Ouma.
（亞里沙）決めなさい　桜満会長。
決断するのは
上に立つ者の仕事です。
It's the person at the
top's job to make the calls.
I found it while I was
cleaning the student council room.
（生徒）生徒会室を
掃除してるときに見つけたの。
What's with this "Void ranking system"?!
どういうことだよ
ヴォイドランク制って！
（生徒）俺たち　みんな
最低ランクじゃないか。
All of us are in the lowest rank!
"Souta Tamadate"
（生徒）じゃあ　俺ら
見捨てられんのか？
So are they going to just give up on us?!
Shu.
（颯太）集。→
やらないんだよな？　ランク制。
You're not going to use
the ranking system. Right?
う…　うん。
R-Right...
（颯太）集にさ　頼みがあるんだ。→
Listen, we have a favor to ask.
俺たちのヴォイド
出してくれないか？
Will you draw out our Voids?
Huh? Why?
どうして？
練習したいんだ。
We want to practice.
My Void was super-useful
when you used it before, wasn't it?
俺のヴォイド　お前が使ったときはすげえ役に立ったんだろ？
でも　俺が使うと
缶詰開けるのが精いっぱいで…。→
But when I use it myself,
it's all I can do to open a can...
練習すれば　もう少し使えるようになるんじゃないかって。
I think maybe I can get a
little better with it if I practice.
なあ　頼むよ　集！
（生徒）お願い！
Okay? Please, Shu!
桜満君！
（生徒）会長！
Please!
Ouma!
Mr. President!
（生徒）役に立ちたいんだよ！
（生徒）なっ　頼むよ。
- We want to be useful!
- Please!
（生徒）取り出してくれよ。
（生徒）桜満君！
- Draw them out!
- Ouma!
[TEL]（嘘界）来ますよ。　ワクチンが
足りなくなった彼らは　必ずね。
They'll come. Now that they
don't have enough of the vaccine,
they're certain to.
They're just a bunch of students.
Is it worth sending me out for them?
（ダリル）相手は　ただの学生でしょ。わざわざ　僕が出張ること？
[TEL]（嘘界）ダリル少尉。→
Lieutenant, when that patriotic young man
先日　葬儀社メンバーを引き渡す
という愛国少年が来たとき→
offered to hand over Funeral
Parlor members the other day,
あなた　撃たなかったでしょう？
（ダリル）ハッ！
you didn't shoot, now did you?
（嘘界）妙な噂を立てられる前に→
Hadn't you better prove that
Daryl Yan can pull the trigger
証明しておいた方が
いいんじゃないですか？
（嘘界）「ダリル・ヤンは撃てる」と。
before any unfortunate rumors spread?
当たり前だ！
Of course I can!
[TEL]（通話の切れる音）
（嘘界）あ痛た。
Ouch.
やりますね！→
You're quite good at this.
さすが　葬儀社の参謀殿。
Just what I'd expect from
Funeral Parlor's chief advisor.
（四分儀）本当なんだろうな。
Can I assume you're telling the truth
when you say that when I win this game,
このゲームに勝ったら
彼に会わせるというのは。
you'll let me see him?
フッ。
勝てたらですよ。
That's if you can win.
≪（扉の開く音）
（祭）やっぱり　ここにいた。
I thought you'd be here.
Everyone's been looking for you.
みんな捜してたよ。
ちょっと失敗してさ…。
落ち込んでたんだ。
I screwed up a little, and got depressed.
What did you screw up?
（祭）何を失敗したの？
うん…。
Well, lots of things, but really...
いや　色々あるけど　結局は→
僕が　人の顔色ばっかり
見てるところだ。
It's about how I only ever think
about what people want to hear.
In front of Yahiro I agree with Yahiro,
谷尋の前では　谷尋に。
颯太の前では　颯太に→
and in front of Souta I agree
with Souta... I bend so easily.
簡単に　なびく。
それは　みんな　そうだよ。
Everyone's like that! Is it so wrong?
それじゃ駄目なの？
駄目でしょ　リーダーは　それじゃ。
Of course it is, for a leader.
もっと強くならなくちゃ。
I have to be stronger.
祭？
Hare?
It's okay. I know lots of your good points, Shu.
（祭）大丈夫。　私　集のいいところ
いっぱい知ってるよ。
集は　大きな音　立てないよね。
You never make loud noises.
椅子に座るときでも
物を置くときでも→
Whether you're sitting in a
chair or putting something down,
you do it softly, don't you?
そっとするでしょう。→
断言したりしないのも好き。
And I love that you don't
go around declaring things.
Only because I don't have confidence.
自信がないだけだよ。
あっ！
Hare... when you say "love"?
祭　「好き」って？
（祭）見ないで。
Don't look!
ごめんね。　ホントは
言うつもりなんか　なかったのに。
I'm sorry.
Really I never meant to
say that to you, and now...
（着信音）
（花音）桜満君？　今　魂館君たちが
学校の外に出たわ。
Ouma?
Tamadate and the others just left the school!
Souta?!
「颯太が？」
（花音）みんなヴォイドを持ってるの。→
They're all holding Voids.
Does that mean you okayed this?
桜満君が許可したってこと？
（颯太）この先に
救急指定の病院があるんだ。
There's an emergency hospital up ahead.
病院ならありそうね　ワクチン。
A hospital would probably have the vaccine.
颯太。　バカなことは　よせよ！
（颯太）バカって何だよ！
Souta! Don't do anything stupid!
What do you mean, "stupid"?
You trying to say I'm stupid because I'm Rank F?
Ｆランクだから
バカって言いたいのか！？
We're going to bring back the vaccine
俺たちは　ワクチンを持って帰って
最低ランクじゃないって証明する！
and prove we're not the lowest rank!
Wait, is that what you were planning
when you asked me for your Voids?
もしかして　最初から
そのつもりで　僕にヴォイドを！？
お前だって　嘘ついてたんだから
これで　おあいこだろ。
You lied, too, so we're even now!
違う！　僕は　嘘なんか…。
No! I didn't lie...
≪（爆発音）
（祭）キャー！
The Anti Bodies!
アンチボディズ！？
みんな逃げて！
Run, all of you! Hide in a building!
建物に隠れるんだ！
（生徒たち）あーっ！
（生徒）あっ！
（生徒）囲まれてる！
We're surrounded!
We're done for...
（生徒）もう駄目だ！
Everyone use your Voids to fight!
みんな　ヴォイドを使って戦うんだ！そんな…！
But...
（生徒）キャッ！
（生徒）助けてー！
Help me!
（祭）大丈夫！？
Are you okay?!
I'll draw them away!
僕が引き付ける！
（操縦士）桜満　集　発見。
We found Shu Ouma.
（ダリル）「生きていたのか！」→
He's alive?!
「そいつを最優先で追え！」→
Going after him is your top priority!
「桜満　集が　生きてるってことは
あの　ちんちくりんも…」→
If Shu Ouma is alive... then is the runt, too?
「おっと…。
今日は　そういうのは　なしだ」
Whoops, today's not the time for that.
Hare! Fix that car over there!
祭！　あそこの車を直してくれ！
（祭）車？
Car?
So we can escape!
Shu's in danger too if we don't!
（颯太）逃げるんだよ！
このままじゃ　集だって危ないだろ。
颯太？
Souta?
何してるんだ？
What's he doing?
急いでくれ！
（祭）ま…　待って！
Please, hurry up!
H-Hold on!
Bandages?
（ダリル）「包帯？　それで
車を直そうだなんて　甘いね！」
If you think I'll let you fix a
car with those, you're dreaming!
逃げろ　祭！
Run, Hare!
キャーッ！
祭！
Hare!
I can't believe Shu, going out on his own...
集のやつ　勝手に出ていって…！
自分の立場が分かってるのか！？
Does he understand his position?
来たよ！
戦闘ヘリ３。　エンドレイヴ４。
They're here! Three choppers and four Endlaves!
（ダリル）「フン！　新手か」
（パイロット）「どうします？」
Reinforcements, eh?
What now, Sir?
（ダリル）「決まってるだろ。
今回の　僕らの任務は皆殺しだ！」
What do you think?
Today's mission is to kill 'em all!
（颯太）何なんだよ…。
What is this?
何なんだよ！
What is this?!
キャー！
離れろ！
いい的だ！
Get some distance! This is a good target!
あぁ…　あっ…。
あっ　うっ…。
あぁ…。　あっ！
集！
Shu!
No...
そんな…。　うっ！
♪♪～
（祭）《ねえ　集》→
Hey, Shu... Have you ever read a
picture book called The Kind King?
《『やさしい王様』って絵本
読んだことある？》→
《その王様は
とても優しくてね》→
The king was really kind...
《みんなに　お金をあげたり→
He gave everyone money... and land...
土地を譲ったりしていたら→
とうとう
国が　なくなってしまったの》→
...until finally... the country was gone.
《王様は
みんなに怒られちゃうんだけど→
The people were all mad at the king...
でも　私は→
But I...
そんな王様が大好きだった》→
...really loved him.
《たぶん　私の初恋》→
I think he was my first love.
《集は　その王様に似てるの》→
You're like that king, Shu...
《優しくて　損しちゃうところが》
...the way you lose out
because of your kindness...
Hey, there's one over there.
おい。　あそこに１人いるぞ。
You know what? I think
you're going to be a great king.
（祭）《私ね　集は　きっと
いい王様になると思うな》→
《だから…》
So...
（祭）あっ！
Is Shu?
（祭）集は…？
よかった。
Thank... goodness...
集に　あげる。→
Shu... I'll give you... my...
私の…。
♪♪～
うっ…　あぁ。
あれ？　何だ…？
Huh? What happened?
Hare!
祭！
ああっ！　ああああ！
あっ…！！
祭！　あああ！
Hare!
あっ！
ああぁぁぁ！！
あぁぁ！！
あっ！
Shu...
集。
ハッ…！
嫌！
No!
あっ！
So you've shown yourself, Shu Ouma.
（ダリル）「出てきたな。　桜満　集！」
（ダリル）うっ！
何だと…！？
You're kidding...
うああっ！！
あれが　集？
Is that... really Shu?
何だ？
What?
Y-You bastard!
（パイロット）「貴様！」
♪♪～
Shu!
（颯太）集！→
集！→
Shu!
I'm sorry! It's my fault!
ごめん！　俺のせいだ！→
It's because I asked Hare to fix that car!
俺が　祭に
車を直してなんて　頼んだから！
そうだよ。
That's right.
えっ？
（綾瀬）集！
Shu!
祭が死んだのは　君のせいだ。
It's your fault Hare died.
Because you took Hare out
there for your own stupid vanity.
君が　くだらない見えで
祭を連れ出したからだ。
集…。
だから　言っただろうが！！
Shu...
Didn't I tell you?!
集！　やめなさい！
Shu, stop it!
お前のせいで　祭が死んだ！
Hare died because of you!
生き返らせろ！
Bring her back! You bring her back to life!
お前が　生き返らせろ！！
ごめん！　ごめん　集！！
I'm sorry! I'm sorry, Shu!
Hare... believed... in me...
祭は　僕を信じて…。
「いいとこ　いっぱいある」って…。
She said I had... lots of good points...
祭…。
Hare!
集！
Shu!
（谷尋）ほら。　もういいだろう。
Come on, that's enough.
（谷尋）集！
Shu?!
僕が間違っていた。
I was wrong.
Kindness is pointless.
優しさになんか　何の意味もない。
（綾瀬）あっ…。
We have to separate the good from the trash.
くずは　区別しなくちゃならない。
I'm going to become king.
僕は　王になる。
♪♪～
What am I supposed to care about,
left behind alone in a world like that?
I spent so many days,
accumulated so many feelings
And you were by my side the whole time,
A fixture of my life, and when you left,
I discovered their weight for the first time
If I'd gripped your hand tight
that day and not let go...
In the end, I was only living
in my own self-satisfied world
"Now it's like I'm a liar
for saying I did it all for you"
Even those murmured words don't reach you
Run, run to you
Watch, I'll fall as often,
get lost as often as it takes
Wait for me, because I'm on my way
No matter what difficulties are waiting there